53. Unusual Taboos. All cultures have taboos, things that are not allowed. Many taboos come
from religion and ancient traditions. What may be perfectly normal in one culture can
be terribly offensive in another. Many taboos are about food and clothing. Are you eating
now? What time is it? In Portugal, you shouldn't eat oranges at night. In Cape Verde, they
say the same thing about sweet potatoes. Some taboos are about what you shouldn't eat. In
America, eating dog or horse meat is taboo, as is eating most insects. In other places,
these foods are fine. Many people in India would never eat beef, but in most of the rest
of the world, people raise cows for meat. The way people eat is also ruled by taboos. In China,
you can eat with your mouth open, whereas in Europe, this is rude. In many parts of the world,
eating with the left hand is taboo because it is used for washing yourself. Clothing taboos
often show social status. Many cultures use colors to show rank. In ancient Rome,
only senators could wear purple. Some taboos are about what skin people can show. In the past,
to see a woman's ankle was taboo. Now we have bikinis. In India, traditional saris show women's
stomachs, but these clothes would be taboo in much of the Middle East. And in Tonga, it is illegal
for a man to go without a shirt in public. Understanding taboos helps us understand other
cultures' histories since most taboos come from the distant past. Learning about other cultures'
taboos also helps us understand our own. After all, any one of our taboos could seem strange
to a foreigner.